The end of an empire...the beginning of a legend.
The Last Legion is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Doug Lefler.
As the Roman empire crumbles, young Romulus Augustus flees the city and embarks on
a perilous voyage to Britain to track down a legion of supporters.
Aurelius, played by Colin Firth.
Ambrosinus, played by Ben Kingsley.
Mira, played by Aishwarya Rai Bachchan.
Odoacer, played by Peter Mullan.
Wulfila, played by Kevin McKidd.
Nestor, played by John Hannah.
The Last Legion is a 2007 historical action adventure film directed
by Doug Lefler and  produced by Dino De Laurentiis.
It is based on the 2002 novel of the same name by Valerio Massimo Manfredi.
It stars Colin Firth, Ben Kingsley, Aishwarya Rai, Thomas Brodie-Sangster,
Peter Mullan, Kevin McKidd, John Hannah, and Iain Glen.
It premiered in Abu Dhabi on 6 April 2007.
The film is loosely inspired by the events of 5th-century European
history, notably the collapse of the Western Roman Empire.
This is coupled with other facts and legends from the history of Britain and fantastic
elements from the legend of King Arthur to provide a basis for the Arthurian legend.
The film explores themes of roman empire, sword, emperor, druid, ancient rome.